You ever felt like you're stuck in life?
Like you're just not free? I felt that
multiple times in my life, especially
when I was in prison. When I was 19
years old, I ran away barefoot and
shirtless from five police units in
rural Georgia, and nobody saw me for
almost two years. They caught me two
days after my 21st birthday, and I did
two and a half years in prison. When I
was released 15 years ago, I immediately
set out doing exactly what everybody
else told me because I figured what I
was doing was not working. The goal set
before me was be a productive member of
society, and that's what I did. Got a
job. I met a girl. I got a better job.
Got married. Got my builder's license. I
bought my first house. I bought another
house. I got my electrical license, and
I kept going, stacking possessions and
things that society had told me to do in
order to fit in. I chaired meetings in
AA. I stayed sober for 13 years. Hell, I
won ultramarathons, and it worked. I
built a $7 million portfolio without a
mortgage, was married with two kids,
living on six acres in a perfect house,
and everything was right, except for me.
There was something inside of me trying
to get out, but it couldn't because it
was blocked off. I felt like I was
screaming without a mouth, and now I
know why. I was living a complete lie.
See, the more I put into the system, the
further it sucked me in. Sucked me into
their ideologies, into their lifestyle,
into their plastic commercialism and
capitalism. I found that part of me was
dying. I was living a life measured by
metrics like money and matrimony and
materialism. One day, it ended out of
the blue. My wife told me she was still
a lesbian and wanted a divorce, and the
dream life came crashing down. Can
anybody identify with working their ass
off and doing everything everybody told
them and actually succeeding at it, just
to have it taken away from them by
somebody who betrayed them? I'd given
her everything, but it wasn't enough.
They say your lowest point is the path
to your highest self. And they're right,
cuz after she told me she wanted a
divorce, I bought my first van. Because
I needed solar, I started with solar
power. Then I started traveling the US.
Then I started traveling the world, and
now I'm off-grid in Costa Rica, and I'm
living the life I've always wanted to
live. But it wasn't easy. I feel like
there's a ton of people out there who
identify with the things I'm telling
them. I'm out. I'm free. I'm out of the
system. I'm growing all my food here. I
got lobster and tilapia in the pond. I
have a solar system over there. There's
no debt on the property. I figured it
out. But now, what do I do? Have
everything I want. I'm not sure, but I
think what I should do now is help other
people walk the same path to freedom
that I have. My name is Joe Fells. I
live for freedom, not finance. And one
day, maybe I'll help you find your free,
just like me.